Hello, I'm Oleg Sidorkin.
大家好！我是 Oleg Sidorkin
I'm a Principal Software Architect at Bluescape. 4-p
是来自 Bluescape 的首席软件架构师。 4-p
I'm also one of the developers of co-browsing technology
也是协同浏览器技术开发人员
and that's what I'm going to be talking about today.
这也将是我今天演讲的主题。
The pandemic and the shift to remote work has challenged
全球疫情以及当下的远程工作模式
the collaboration work landscape all together.
改变了大家的协同工作环境。
When previously gathering a team in one room
之前人们汇集在同一个地方
behind a high definition screen was a no-brainer,
的高清屏幕下是轻而易举的，
today it has become a challenge
如今则变得不再容易
and probably not coming back anytime soon.
而且短期内也不会再回到从前。
Classic video conferencing and assets sharing tools
传统的网络会议和资源共享工具
are not adapted for group work when it comes to
不适合小组工作，当涉及
high fidelity content such as art, animations, and video. 16-p
高保真内容时，例如艺术、动画、视频等。 16-p
We at Bluescape created a novel approach
我们在 Bluescape 找到了一种新方法
where virtually any web site or web enabled tool
任何网站或基于 web 的工具
can gain additional functionality for live co-experience
都可以获得额外的功能，提供实时协同体验
in viewing, commenting and editing creative content.
来检查、评论、编辑创造性内容。
When a user or a team starts a co-browsing session,
当用户或团队开始一个共享会议时，
the desired web site is loaded in the cloud
所需的网页在云端加载
while exact replicas and all incremental changes
而精准副本和所有增量的变化
are broadcasted to all connected clients,
均传递给所有关联的客户端，
giving them the same quality, the same latency,
给予它们相同的质量、延迟
and about the same experience as they would browse
以及相同的体验，正如浏览
the content on their local device
本地设备上的内容
or behind the same screen. 29-p
或者同一屏幕后的内容。 29-p
On the server side, we use Chromium as a headless
在服务器端，我们使用 Chromium 作为 headless
web browser thanks to its open source nature and
网页浏览器，这得益于它的开源特性
availability of a mature Chrome DevTools Protocol (CDP).
以及成熟的 Chrome 开发工具协议（CDP）。
Another point to consider was 65% browser
另一个需要考虑的是
market share worldwide earned by Chrome.
Chrome 占有全球 65% 的浏览器份额。
We selected old fashioned WebSockets as a low latency
我们选取老式的 WebSockets 作为一种低延迟的
communication protocol that guarantees
通信协议，确保
in-order messages delivery.
消息的正确传递。
The challenges start when we try to capture
当我们尝试捕捉
and deliver a live and exact replica of a web page
并向远程客户端交付实时的精准复制的网页时
to the remote client. 41-p
就会产生问题。 41-p
W3C DOM4 introduced MutationObserver deprecating
W3C DOM4 引入 MutationObserver
Mutation Events. MutationObserver is a great way to
弃用 Mutation Events。MutationObserver 是一种很好的方式
get notified about changes in the DOM,
来获取关于 DOM 中的变动通知。
but it doesn't provide enough information
但它没有提供足够的信息
to understand what was the exact change
来理解确切的变化是什么
and to form an incremental DOM update
并形成一个增量的 DOM 更新
to be broadcasted to connected clients.
并传递给连接的客户端。
We ended up with injected JavaScript code
我们最终注入了一些 JavaScript 代码
that translates browser DOM into a virtual DOM
将浏览器 DOM 转换为虚拟 DOM
and computes the difference between the previous
并计算差异
and the new version of the virtual DOM.
虚拟 DOM 的新旧版本之间的差异。
To keep cost of computation at bay,
为了保持计算成本
we used persistent data structures and hints
我们使用了持久数据结构和 MutationObserver 提供的提示
from MutationObserver about each area that were affected.
针对每个受影响的区域。
The immutability of virtual DOM allowed us to
虚拟 DOM 的不变性让我们能够
leverage shallow comparison via triple equal
通过三重相等的 JavaScript 运算符，
JavaScript operator so we can skip analysis
利用浅比较，这样我们可以跳过
of entire sub trees if we know that
对整个子树的分析，
they will not be affected for sure. 61-p
在我们知道它们肯定不会受到影响的前提下。 61-p
It works well for almost all DOM elements,
它几乎适用于所有 DOM 元素，
but there are some exceptions to take care of.
但也有一些例外。
MutationObserver doesn't sense changes in
MutationObserver 不会感知画布元素的变化
canvas elements and information extraction from
从画布上下文中提取的信息
canvas context poses its own challenge.
也带来一些问题。
We use mixed approach. For less dynamic canvases,
我们使用混合方案。对于较少动态的画布，
like charts, we extract content as data URL
例如图表，我们提取内容作为数据 URL
that becomes a special attribute in virtual DOM
这成为虚拟 DOM 中的一个特殊属性
so the same synchronization logic can be used
因此，可以使用相同的同步逻辑
as for regular elements.
就像常规元素一样。
For canvases with highly dynamic content
对于具有高动态内容的画布
and specifically for WebGL ones,
特别是 WebGL，
we have an experimental approach based on
我们找到了一种实验方法，是基于
captureStream API and WebRTC video streaming. 76-p
captureStream API 和 WebRTC 视频流的。 76-p
The document attached MutationObserver
附加 MutationObserver 的文档
doesn't sense changes in Shadow DOM
不会感知 Shadow DOM 中的变化
so every such shadowRoot should be observed individually,
所以应该单独观察每一个这样的 shadowRoot，
which adds additional logistics to
这为监控子系统添加了额外工作，
the monitoring subsystem but it's solvable.
但它是可以解决的。
However, additionally, Shadow DOM trees created
然而，在封闭模式下创建的 Shadow DOM 树
in closed mode become invisible for JavaScript.
对 JavaScript 变得不可见。
In this case we either should give up
这种情况，我们要么应该放弃，
or we can, and what we do, we monkey-patch
要么解决它，而我们所做的就是，
attachShadow method of the Element to keep them open.
对元素的 attachShadow 方法采用猴子补丁，来保持它们的开放状态。
It might contradict certain web site logic but that works. 88-p
它可能与某些网站逻辑相矛盾，但确实有效。 88-p
When we serve content of a web page to
当我们把网页内容提供给
all connected clients,
所有关联客户端时，
we have to introduce certain modifications to it.
我们必须对其进行某种修改。
We strip out all JavaScript code,
我们去除了所有的 JavaScript 代码，
effectively making the web page passive and embeddable,
有效地让网页变得被动和可嵌入，
so it even can bypass the iframe embed implementations.
因此它甚至可以绕过 iframe 嵌入实现。
All JavaScript logic is executed
所有 JavaScript 逻辑
in the cloud in headless browser.
都在 headless 浏览器的云端执行。
We patch links to external assets
我们修补外部资源链接，
so all of them are served from the cloud as well.
因此所有这些服务也都来自云端。
No direct access.
无法直接访问。
Those are target web sites.
这些是目标网站。
We infuse event handlers to intercept
我们注入事件处理程序来截取
clients interactions in the page
页面中的客户端交互，
and reroute them to the cloud instance of the web site.
并将它们重新连接到网站的云端事例。 这样的拦截允许我们引入真正的共同浏览体验
experience when the single instance of the web site
当网站的单个事例
can be effectively controlled and viewed
可以被多个分散式客户端
by multiple distributed clients. 108-p
有效地控制和查看时。 108-p
And there are more challenges to come. 110-p
未来还有更多挑战。 110-p
The event handlers distinguish “trusted” events
事件处理程序区分由用户操作生成的
generated by user action
“可信”事件
and synthetic events generated or modified
和由脚本生成或修改的
by script or dispatched via dispatchEvent API.
或是通过 dispatchEvent API 发送的合成事件。
This feature is effectively employed by certain web sites
某些网站有效地利用了这一功能
to ensure genuinity of the user input.
来确保用户输入的真实性。
The workaround we found so far is to dispatch
到目前为止，我们找到的解决方案是
such events through Chrome DevTools protocol.
通过 Chrome DevTools 协议来处理此类事件。
And in this case, they become trusted events. 119-p
在这种情况下，它们成为可信事件。 119-p
Patching of external assets becomes tricky
当涉及异常内容时，
when it comes to malformed content.
修补外部资源变得棘手。
For example, a browser might ignore a set of errors
例如，浏览器可能忽略
in CSS file and still displays the valid part
CSS 文件中的一组错误，但仍然显示有效部分
while the most of CSS parsing libraries
而 node.js 生态系统中的大多 CSS 解析库
in node.js ecosystem will fail to process it.
将无法处理它们。
The current solution that we use is
我们当下使用的解决方案是
to mimic the browser behavior as close as possible,
尽可能模仿浏览器的行为，
effectively taking such logic,
有效地提取这种逻辑，
such CSS code handling from browser's code base,
从浏览器代码库中解析出这样的 CSS 代码，
thanks to its open source nature. 131-p
这得益于它的开源特性。 131-p
We also found that page synchronization logic is
我们还发现页面同步逻辑
sensitive to intrusive browser extensions,
对那些可以在客户端启用的
that can be enabled on the client side.
侵入式的浏览器扩展很敏感。
Some DOM changes are positional
一些 DOM 更改是位置上的
and if an extension altered browser DOM
而且如果一个扩展以意想不到的方式改变了浏览器 DOM，
in an unexpected way, the sync protocol
那么同步协议
might get confused.
可能会混淆。
As a partial mitigation of this issue,
为了一定程度上缓解这个问题，
we introduced unique identifiers to key DOM elements.
我们为关键 DOM 元素引入了唯一标识符。
JavaScript also doesn't expose object pointers and
JavaScript 也不公开对象指针和
any kind of object identity, so we used a tree,
任何类型的对象标识，因此我们使用了树结构，
we leveraged a distinguish property of a Map container
我们利用了 Map 容器的一个区别属性
where key can be any value including DOM element.
其中 key 可以是任意值，包括 DOM 元素。
Maintaining such a map aside allowed us to introduce
保留这样一个映射，可以让我们
unique identitiers and object pointers for DOM elements,
为 DOM 元素引入唯一的标识符和对象指针
and keep the original DOM intact
并保持原始 DOM 的完整性
without introducing interference with Web site logic. 149-p
而不对网站逻辑产生干扰。 149-p
Implementing co-browsers, we faced many challenges,
实现协同浏览，我们面临着许多挑战，
and I described just maybe a quarter of them.
我可能只描述了其中的四分之一。
A significant part of them is related to limitations
一个非常重要的部分是与
or design decisions in corresponding web technologies.
相关 Web 技术的限制或设计决策有关。
And it's understandable because what we're doing is not
这是可以理解的，因为我们做的并不是
what you are typically doing.
大家通常所做的。
We are trying to implement completely remote
我们正尝试实现完全的
browsing experience.
远程浏览体验。
For most of such issues, we managed either
对于大多问题，我们要么设法
to find workaround or to introduce certain hacks
找到了解决办法，要么引入了一些
leveraging dynamic nature of the web stack.
利用 Web 堆栈动态特性的技巧。
So when it works, it works perfect, it works flawlessly.
因此，当它行得通时，一切完美。
When it doesn't, finding solution is tricky,
行不通时，寻求解决方案就很棘手
it feels like walking through a minefield.
这感觉就像穿越雷区一样。
But at the end, it's doable. 165-p
但最终将是可行的。 165-p
Thank you.
谢谢大家。